https://www.envigo.com/privacy-policy

Research models
We offer you the experience, quality, and consistency that is essential to your success.
Find research models
Models by therapeutic area
Oncology model sampling program (North America)
Oncology model sampling program (Europe)
Pricing
How to select the right oncology model
Discover critical factors to consider when selecting your animal model and why
Download e-book
Advances in immunodeficient mouse models
The R2G2 brings a new option to oncology and immunology researchers
Download white paper
Research services
Research services
Our research services operating group provides high-quality support services worldwide.
Genetically engineered models and services (GEMS)
Research model support services
Choosing a commercial partner for large-scale rederivation projects of laboratory animal facilities
Tackle your biggest rederivation hurdles with help from our experienced project managers
Stream the webinar
Antibody optimization
Learn how antibodies may be used to support the development of therapeutic products
Download white paper
Teklad diet, bedding and enrichment
Teklad diet, bedding and enrichment
What comes out of your research depends in large part on what goes into your research models. Ensuring your study animals have the most appropriate diet is critical to maintaining consistent, reliable research data.
Learn more
Ask a nutritionist
Live chat
Teklad diet selector
Get recommendations
Teklad laboratory animal diets
Standard natural ingredient diets
Custom research diets
Scientific insights
Keep up to date with the latest scientific developments in your industry.
Learn more
Key considerations for choosing a rodent surgical model
Download e-book
Tips for selecting a genetic testing provider
Download e-book
Animal diets
Antibody production
Bedding and enrichment
Contract breeding
Diet-induced obesity
Genetic testing
Health monitoring
Reproductive-toxicology (DART)
Research models
Surgical services
Toxicology
CLOSE ×
Research models
Back
Research models
Find research models
Models by therapeutic area
Oncology model sampling program (NA)
Oncology model sampling program (EU)
Pricing
Back
Insights
Animal diets
Antibody production
Bedding and enrichment
Contract breeding
Diet induced obesity
Genetic testing
Health monitoring
Reproductive toxicology (DART)
Research models
Surgical services
Research services
Back
Research services
Genetically engineered models and services (GEMS)
Full spectrum health monitoring
Custom antibody production services
Biological products and services
Contract breeding services
Tumor models and services
Genetic testing services
Surgical services
Research model support services
Health monitoring
Reproductive toxicology (DART)
Research models
Surgical services
Teklad diet, bedding and enrichment
Back
Teklad diet, bedding, enrichment
Standard natural ingredient diets
Custom research diets
Medicated diets
Health monitoring
Reproductive toxicology (DART)
Research models
Surgical services
Resources
Back
Resources
Cell line references
Health monitoring reports
Genetic monitoring reports
Health monitoring
Reproductive toxicology (DART)
Research models
Surgical services
Insights
Back
Insights
Animal diets
Antibody production
Bedding and enrichment
Contract breeding
Diet induced obesity
Genetic testing
Health monitoring
Reproductive toxicology (DART)
Research models
Surgical services
About
News and events
Locations
Careers
Contact
Blog
Home +
Privacy policy
Privacy policy
Last Updated 10 November 2020
Envigo respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you what personal information we may collect about you when you interact with Envigo and its group of companies (“Envigo,” “we,” “us,” and “our,”), how we look after your personal data and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.
It is important that you read this Privacy Policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data.
This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.
This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.
Third-party links
This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
1. The data we collect about you
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).
We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:
Identity Data includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier, title, date of birth and gender.
Contact Data includes, email address and telephone numbers, job title, IP Address, employer.
Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
Profile Data includes your username, areas of research, areas of interest, preferences, feedback and survey responses, role in purchasing
Usage Data includes information about how you use our website.
Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.
We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
If you fail to provide personal data
Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.
2. How is your personal data collected?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity and Contact by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email, website, digital platforms or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
apply for our products or services;
subscribe to our service or publications;
request access to or be sent marketing content
enter a competition, promotion, survey or register for an event; or
give us some feedback.
Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie statement for further details.
Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:
Technical Data from the following parties:(a) analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU, (b) advertising networks,(c) search information providers.
Identity and Contact Data from publicly availably sources such as relevant Company Registers.
3. How we use your personal data
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Where it is necessary to protect the vital interests of the individual or another person.
Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending direct marketing communications. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by visiting our contact preference center or by contacting us directly. A link to our contact preference center is available in all email communications.
Purposes for which we will use your personal data
We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/Activity
Type of data
Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest
To register you as a new customer
(a) Identity(b) Contact
Performance of a contract
To manage our relationship with you which will include:(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or Privacy Policy(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey.
(a) Identity(b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)
To enable you to complete a survey, sign up for an event, subscribe for information or updates.
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Usage (e) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you (b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)
(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Technical
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant website content, general marketing and messaging to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Usage (e) Marketing and Communications (f) Technical
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform and measure our marketing strategy)
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
(a) Technical (b) Usage
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical (d) Usage (e) Profile
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)
Marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising, via the contact preference center, available in all email communications, or by contacting us at any time.
Promotional offers from us
We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you.
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition, registered for a promotion or for an event and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
Third-party marketing
We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the Envigo group of companies for marketing purposes.
Opting out
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time via the contact preference center, available in all email communications, or by contacting us at any time.
Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, product/service experience or other transactions.
Cookies
You can set your browser to refuse all, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our cookie statement.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
4. Disclosures of your personal data
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 3 above.
Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary below.
External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary below.
Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
5. International transfers
We share your personal data within the Envigo Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
Some of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.
Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented.
We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission.
Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.
Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield (to the extent that it continues to provide adequate safeguards) which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.
6. Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
7. Data retention
How long will you use my personal data for?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
8. Your legal rights
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. You may be entitled to:
Request access to your personal data.
Request correction of your personal data.
Request erasure of your personal data.
Object to processing of your personal data.
Request restriction of processing your personal data.
Request transfer of your personal data.
Right to withdraw consent.
You also have the right to complain to your local data protection authority if your privacy rights are violated, or if you have suffered as a result of unlawful processing of your personal information. We would however welcome the opportunity to resolve any issue that you have.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.
No fee usually required
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
What we may need from you
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
Time limit to respond
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
9. Glossary
LAWFUL BASIS
Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.
Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.
Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
THIRD PARTIES
Internal Third Parties
Other companies in the Envigo Group acting as joint controllers or processors and who are based in the USA, Europe and ROW and provide products and services and IT and system administration services and undertake leadership reporting.
External Third Parties
Service providers acting as processors who provide IT and system administration services.
Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
YOUR LEGAL RIGHTSYou have the right to:
Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
Meet BradGien
Global Head of Surgery
View Profile View Profile
Scientific Insights
Keep up-to-date with the latest industry thinking and scientific insights
Explore today Explore today
Subscribe to updates from Envigo
Sign up and you’ll receive the latest updates that matter to you, delivered straight to your inbox.
Oncology model sampling program (North America)
Oncology model sampling program (Europe)
Genetically engineered models and services (GEMS)
